# **GEORGIOS VASILAKIS**

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Motivated team player with experience developing, deploying, and maintaining software solutions. Well-educated in developing applications for a wide range of industries, including healthcare, administrative services, and sports & leisure. Well-versed in using cutting-edge technologies, such as React and Angular to create powerful front-end solutions.

#### **EDUCATION**

# School of Electrical and Computer Engineering

Technical University of Crete, Chania

Thesis: "Blockchain smart contract system for secure health data sharing"

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# UI/UX | Web Developer

January 2020 - Present | Freelancer, Athens

- Created interactive websites that were both visually appealing and functionally sound.
- Developed web-based user interfaces for multiple applications using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Experienced with social media and communications platforms.

# Front-End Developer

July 2021 - July 2023 | Elta Courier, Athens

- Collaborated closely with the back-end developers to integrate API calls into the front-end codebase.
- Evaluated and recommended server hardware and software.
- Utilized modern frameworks like AngularJS and Node.js for developing interactive client-side applications.
- Created technical requirements and worked with engineering team to develop, test and launch functionality on time and with high quality.
- Integrated third-party libraries and APIs into existing applications for improved functionality.



#### PROFESSIONAL SITE

https://g979-personalsite.web.app/

# CONTACT

- 694 442 8973
- g979design@gmail.com
- Athens 15235

#### **SKILLS**

- Web Technologies: AngularJS, jQuery, Bootstrap
- React
- JavaScript
- WordPress Proficiency
- Graphic and User Interface Design
- DevOps Engineering

# **LANGUAGES**

- Greek
   Native
- English
   Fluent
   ECPE
- German

Conversational Goethe-Zertifikat B2

# Junior Front End Developer

September 2018 - November 2019 | Nostos Software Sol., Athens

- Performed debugging tasks using browser developer tools such as Firebug or Chrome DevTools.
- Applied best practices in coding standards, semantic markup, SEO optimization techniques.
- Collaborated closely with the back-end developers to integrate API calls into the front-end codebase.
- Created UI components with reusable codes for a better user experience.
- Used version control systems such as Git to manage source code repositories in a team environment.

# **UDEMY COURSES COMPLETED**

- Ethereum and Solidity: The Complete Developer's Guide by Stephan Grider
- React The Complete Guide 2023 (incl. React Router & Redux)
- Angular The Complete Guide (2023 Edition)
- Project Development Using Spring Boot
- The Complete Front-End Web Development Course